<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xd:xmlBankDriverSpec xmlns:xd="http://www.jsynthlib.org/xmldevice"><xd:name>Yamaha DX7 Performance Bank</xd:name><xd:infoText>This JSynthLib "Yamaha DX7 Mark-I" device
        driver supports the following patch types with librarian and
        editor function: - Voice - Performance (=Function Parameter)
        GENERAL INFORMATION =================== - DX7 MARK-I Because of
        the MIDI implementation of the system ROM of the early units
        (especially the ActiveSensing- and the SysEx-handling), problems
        will occur with an early DX7 in cooperation with patch
        libraries/editors. It's advisable to upgrade early system
        ROMs to a newer version. - DEVICE DRIVER This driver is tested
        with a DX7 in an original state (system ROM V1.8 from October
        24th 1985). Even so there might be some bugs. Since this driver
        uses special methods you should choose this driver only if you
        have a DX7 Mark-I. These special methods concern the
        "Remote Control" function, the "Parameter
        Change" MIDI messages of the performance editor and others.
        I made the experience that you can send a single performance
        patch to the DX7 function edit buffer. At least to a DX7 with
        the described System ROM. At this time only the direction
        JSynthLib->DX7 is working. If a parameter is changed on the
        DX7 itself, JSynthlib doesn't become aware of this. -
        REPORTING BUGS Report bugs to &lt;Torsten.Tittmann@gmx.de>.
        Any feedback about bugs are welcome. Also comments and proposals
        of improvements will be helpful to improve this driver. - TODO
        To extend my driver family to the models DX1 and DX5 I'm
        looking for the MIDI specification of these models. The access
        of the two internal "DX7"s as well as the complete
        specification of the performance patch are unknown. To extend my
        driver family to the model TX216/TX816 in a satisfying manner
        some major changes are necessary for the JSynthLib architecture.
        But since the TF1 modul of the TX216/TX816 is compatible with
        the TX7, a base support is given. DEVICE CONFIGURATION
        ==================== You will find some settings in the device
        configuration to suite the device driver to your preferences: -
        "Synthesizer Name" This is a free choosable
        identifier. It might be useful if you have several DX7 Mark-I
        devices - "Enable Remote Control?" The MIDI
        specification of the DX7 doesn't support requesting of a
        patch. As an alternative this driver can simulate the necessary
        panel button pushes, if you switch on the "Enable Remote
        Control" function. The "Enable Remote Control"
        function makes the SysInfo available, chooses the desired patch
        number, etc. - "Disable Memory Protection?" The
        "Disable Memory Protection?" function will switch off
        the memory protection. - "Display Hints and Tips?" If
        you are familiar with the DX7 you can switch off the message
        windows by disabling the "Display Hints and Tips?"
        function. This will avoid all messages! PATCH TYPE SPECIFIC
        INFORMATION =============================== "VOICE"
        SINGLE/BANK DRIVER/EDITOR The underlying patch is identical at
        least for all members of the "DX7 family" (DX1, DX5,
        DX7, TX7, TX816, DX7s, DX7-II and TX802). This driver also
        supports the use of cartridges with the DX7 as far as possible.
        Of course, you have to use the switches of the cartridges
        themselves to choose bank A or bank B of a "DX7 VOICE
        ROM" cartridge or to switch on/off the memory protection of
        "RAM1" cartridges. Further, the storing of a voice
        bank to a cartridge "RAM1" isn't supported! Only
        those parameters are implemented in the editor, which are stored
        in the patch. So, you won't find any function parameter like
        pitchband, portamento, etc. These are part of the performance
        driver/editor. There is only one exception: the OPERATOR ON/OFF
        buttons, because they are useful for programming.
        "PERFORMANCE" SINGLE DRIVER/EDITOR The underlying
        patch is identical for the DX1, DX5, DX7, TX7 and TX816. But
        only those parameters are displayed in the editor, which are
        evaluated by the DX7. The DX7 supports only the receiving of a
        single performance patch; no transmitting, or requesting.
    </xd:infoText>
    <xd:authors>Torsten Tittmann</xd:authors>
    <xd:patchType>Performance</xd:patchType>
    <xd:patchSize>4104</xd:patchSize>
    <xd:sysexID>F0430*022000</xd:sysexID>
    <xd:patchNumbers>
        <xd:string>01</xd:string>
        <xd:string>02</xd:string>
        <xd:string>03</xd:string>
        <xd:string>04</xd:string>
        <xd:string>05</xd:string>
        <xd:string>06</xd:string>
        <xd:string>07</xd:string>
        <xd:string>08</xd:string>
        <xd:string>09</xd:string>
        <xd:string>10</xd:string>
        <xd:string>11</xd:string>
        <xd:string>12</xd:string>
        <xd:string>13</xd:string>
        <xd:string>14</xd:string>
        <xd:string>15</xd:string>
        <xd:string>16</xd:string>
        <xd:string>17</xd:string>
        <xd:string>18</xd:string>
        <xd:string>19</xd:string>
        <xd:string>20</xd:string>
        <xd:string>21</xd:string>
        <xd:string>22</xd:string>
        <xd:string>23</xd:string>
        <xd:string>24</xd:string>
        <xd:string>25</xd:string>
        <xd:string>26</xd:string>
        <xd:string>27</xd:string>
        <xd:string>28</xd:string>
        <xd:string>29</xd:string>
        <xd:string>30</xd:string>
        <xd:string>31</xd:string>
        <xd:string>32</xd:string>
        <xd:string>33</xd:string>
        <xd:string>34</xd:string>
        <xd:string>35</xd:string>
        <xd:string>36</xd:string>
        <xd:string>37</xd:string>
        <xd:string>38</xd:string>
        <xd:string>39</xd:string>
        <xd:string>40</xd:string>
        <xd:string>41</xd:string>
        <xd:string>42</xd:string>
        <xd:string>43</xd:string>
        <xd:string>44</xd:string>
        <xd:string>45</xd:string>
        <xd:string>46</xd:string>
        <xd:string>47</xd:string>
        <xd:string>48</xd:string>
        <xd:string>49</xd:string>
        <xd:string>50</xd:string>
        <xd:string>51</xd:string>
        <xd:string>52</xd:string>
        <xd:string>53</xd:string>
        <xd:string>54</xd:string>
        <xd:string>55</xd:string>
        <xd:string>56</xd:string>
        <xd:string>57</xd:string>
        <xd:string>58</xd:string>
        <xd:string>59</xd:string>
        <xd:string>60</xd:string>
        <xd:string>61</xd:string>
        <xd:string>62</xd:string>
        <xd:string>63</xd:string>
        <xd:string>64</xd:string>
    </xd:patchNumbers>
    <xd:bankNumbers>
        <xd:string>Internal</xd:string>
    </xd:bankNumbers>
    <xd:deviceIDoffset>2</xd:deviceIDoffset>
    <xd:checksumOffset>4102</xd:checksumOffset>
    <xd:checksumStart>6</xd:checksumStart>
    <xd:checksumEnd>4101</xd:checksumEnd>
    <xd:patchNameStart>0</xd:patchNameStart>
    <xd:patchNameSize>30</xd:patchNameSize>
        <xd:customProperties>
        <xd:customProperty name="dxSysexHeaderSize" value="6" />
        <xd:customProperty name="dxPatchNameOffset" value="34" />
        <xd:customProperty name="dxSinglePackedSize" value="64" />
    </xd:customProperties>
    <xd:trimSize>4104</xd:trimSize>
    <xd:numPatches>64</xd:numPatches>
    <xd:numColumns>4</xd:numColumns>
    <xd:singleSize>102</xd:singleSize>
    <xd:singleSysexID>F0430*01005E</xd:singleSysexID>
</xd:xmlBankDriverSpec>